PABLO TALAVANTE DÍAZ

Madrid, Spain

 $+34\ 619\ 937\ 889 \diamond pablot94@gmail.com \diamond @imaginarybrut$

WHO AM I

I'm the kind of people who thinks Mathematics are fun. After dropping Architecture after two years that opened my mind, I focused my studies in Industrial Engineering on areas that have to do with mathematics and computer science, mainly regarding control theory, programming and optimization. I taught myself Machine Learning and Deep Learning, along with more advanced Mathematics and the most important web technologies. I also have passion for the visual arts and music (I played the bass in a band called Noise Nebula), specially when they intersect with technology and science. I like taking analog pictures, drawing, and making computational art procedurally and using neural nets.

Currently I'm focusing my studies on the state-of-the-art AI and optimization methods, the programming skills needed to implement them and setting them in a production-ready environment, and applying that knowledge to real-world problems. I'm also the main Deep Learning mentor at AI Saturdays Madrid, a non-profit organization which aims to democratize AI to everybody.

EDUCATION

Master's Degree in Systems Engineering and Control	since Oct. 2018
--	-----------------

Universidad Complutense de Madrid / UNED

Bachelor's Degree in Industrial Technologies Engineering Sept. 2014 - Oct. 2018

Universidad Carlos III de Madrid

Intensification in Automation and Electronics

Data Science and Big Data Analytics Oct. 2017 - Jan. 2018

Massachusetts Institute of Technology [MIT xPRO - online]

Big Data Visualization Course Sept. 2017 - Nov. 2017

Synergic Partners and Fundación Telefónica

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sounditi since Nov. 2018

Data Scientist

- · Ideated and formalized the general concept in collaboration with the founder
- · Carried on several interviews in order to form the technological team

U-Care Digital Health

July 2018 - April 2019

Machine Learning Engineer

- · Developed a glucose prediction system for diabetic patients and an API for its use from an external app
- · Developed an ECG classifier using convolutional neural networks
- · Collaborated with Vall d'Hebron Hospital and CSIC (Centro Superior de Investigaciones Científicas)

Synergic Partners (a Telefonica Company)

Feb. 2018 - March 2018

Jan 2016 - Dec. 2016

Professional Internship - Full Stack Developer

· Developed an internal innovation project for data visualization with React.js

Aula de las Artes - Universidad Carlos III de Madrid

Extracurricular Internship

AI EXPERIENCE

Advanced Keras User (Functional API)

Data generators for huge datasets

MLP, CNN, LSTM, Autoencoder, (DC)GAN

Neural weights visualization

Architecture and Hyperparameter tuning heuristics

Genetic Algorithms and Evolutionary Strategies

Principles of Reinforcement Learning and NLP

COMPUTER SKILLS

Proficient Python: scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Keras, pandas, numpy, pymongo, opencv

Intermediate JavaScript, C, C++ and Processing (based on Java)

Web Tools: React.js, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Flask

Excel, Tableau and Carto

AutoCad (2D drawing), Rhinoceros and V-Ray (3D modeling and rendering)

Grasshopper (3D parametric design) and Unity (graphics engine)

Adobe Photoshop, Final Cut Pro X and Logic Pro X (image editing, video and sound)

FURTHER TRAINING

Move37 Siraj Raval's Reinforcement Learning Course The School of AI	2018
Andrew Ng's Machine Learning Course Stanford University	2017
Crash course on Game Development CEV Madrid (30 hours)	2015
Music production course School Overtonica (50 hours)	2014
Grasshopper and parametric design course ETSAM (30 hours)	2013
Course on Architecture and Digital Design Architecture University of Wroclaw (50 hours)	2013
Digital and Analog Photography course ETSAM (30 hours)	2013
VOLUNTEERING	
Deep Learning Mentor AI Saturdays Madrid	2019
Processing Mentor Medialab Prado	2018
LANGUAGES	

Spanish - Native

English - Advanced

Japanese - Elementary

French - Elementary